<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hi there! on Walter Zielenski</title><link>https://www.wjziv.com/</link><description>Recent content in Hi there! on Walter Zielenski</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.wjziv.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Josh's* Challa Bread</title><link>https://www.wjziv.com/20210705-joshs-challah/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.wjziv.com/20210705-joshs-challah/</guid><description>My sister&amp;rsquo;s husband Josh didn&amp;rsquo;t actually create this recipe for bread. It was only with him that I ever made challah for the first time. Proper credit goes to Beth Ricanati.
When we first made this recipe, it had the dense, squishy texture one might expect of an open-oven baked bread with little rise-time. I fully intend to return to this recipe with improvements with regard to rise time, baking in a dutch-oven, and weaving to fit inside a small pan.</description></item><item><title>About This Site</title><link>https://www.wjziv.com/20201126-this-website/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.wjziv.com/20201126-this-website/</guid><description>Summary Host a personal website on Github using the Hugo site generator. Updates to content will be incorporated into the site via triggered Github Actions.
My Choices Originally, I was using Frozen-Flask and FlatPages to build my static site. Flask, as backend tool I was familiar with, was something I was interested in leveraging for this website. Ultimately, it felt like a hodge-podge project, loosely slapped together which could have been executed in a better way.</description></item><item><title>VSCode on the Cloud</title><link>https://www.wjziv.com/20200426-vscode-server/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.wjziv.com/20200426-vscode-server/</guid><description>Goal Using Google Cloud Platform, host an instance of VSCode to access via the browser for ~$25-$50/month. More specifically, we&amp;rsquo;ll be hosting an instance of Code-Server on GCP in a constantly-running VM.
This works as an alternative to the cloud-development environments which may limit the developer in some way:
Number of private repositories Working Hours in a given period Number of projects Repository integration. Requirements This tutorial assumes you have already set up a GCP account and enabled billing.</description></item><item><title>Serious Eats' Workhorse Loaf</title><link>https://www.wjziv.com/20200108-serious-eats-workhorse-loaf/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.wjziv.com/20200108-serious-eats-workhorse-loaf/</guid><description>Serious Eats has a spectacular recipe for a hand-made loaf of whitebread. The only problem is that there are two versions. The short version skips a few steps which improve the rising process. The 5-part long version includes everything for a delicious loaf, but it takes 37 years to read through it all for the action steps.
The first time you make a bread loaf, I recommend you follow along the long-form recipe on the Serious Eats website to find out the &amp;lsquo;right way&amp;rsquo; to execute things like a &amp;lsquo;fold&amp;rsquo; or read up on tips for transferring dough from one bowl to another.</description></item><item><title>Aunt Jo's Christmas Ricotta Cookies</title><link>https://www.wjziv.com/20200107-aunt-jos-cookies/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.wjziv.com/20200107-aunt-jos-cookies/</guid><description>Everybody has an aunt with their own way of making those Italian Christmas cookies.
And I&amp;rsquo;ve discovered that my Aunt Jo has at some point shifted to a second recipe. The time of transition is unknown, and which is the old/new version is a mystery; I simply refuse to ask, because I haven&amp;rsquo;t noticed the difference over time, and I can only dream that I grew on on a &amp;ldquo;better cookie&amp;rdquo;, whicher it may be.</description></item><item><title>Installing Python on ChromeOS</title><link>https://www.wjziv.com/20200105-python-on-chromeos/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.wjziv.com/20200105-python-on-chromeos/</guid><description>Have a Chromebook? Don&amp;rsquo;t have Python installed? Or worse, have Python2 and you&amp;rsquo;d rather have Python3? Let&amp;rsquo;s fix that!
To start out, I want to share a picture from XKCD:
Python is notorious for its ability to lull the developer into a false sense of security before they absentmindedly mis-manage their coding environment. It&amp;rsquo;s unfortunate, and not exactly necessary for a language to require this. Go ahead and search for the golang python enviroment equivalent.</description></item><item><title>SFTP Server Setup</title><link>https://www.wjziv.com/20200104-sftp-server/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.wjziv.com/20200104-sftp-server/</guid><description>Assuming the user has already created a VM with a static IP address open to HTTP/S traffic&amp;hellip;
Creating An SFTP Account SSH into the VM which you&amp;rsquo;d like to turn into a SFTP server.
Create a new account which you&amp;rsquo;d like to provide to users to deposit files:
sudo adduser username sudo passwd username Create the sftp directory and limit the user&amp;rsquo;s access and permissions. Change the username appropriately:</description></item><item><title>GCP VM Setup for Squid Proxy and SFTP</title><link>https://www.wjziv.com/20200103-gcp-vm-setup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.wjziv.com/20200103-gcp-vm-setup/</guid><description>Assuming the user has already opened a GCP Account and enabled billing&amp;hellip;
The goal of this tutorial is to create a server which will be responsive to external HTTP requests for the purpose of serving external users a FTP server to drop files, or operate as an authenticated proxy.
VM Set Up Open Compute Engine &amp;gt; VM Instances. Createa new Instance. (NOTE. If you would like to create a template from which more instances can be made, perform the following steps from Instance Templates.</description></item><item><title>Squid Proxy Server Setup</title><link>https://www.wjziv.com/20200103-squid-proxy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.wjziv.com/20200103-squid-proxy/</guid><description>These instructions assume you have successfully completed the following:
Opened a GCP account. Set up a VM with a static IP address and open HTTP/HTTPS ports. The goal of these instrctions is to create a functional proxy VM on GCP.
Port Rules With your VM already created and tagged correctly, navigate to VPC Network &amp;gt; Firewall Rules. Here, a number of networking rules have been created. We will be editing the HTTP/S port rules.</description></item><item><title>Now</title><link>https://www.wjziv.com/now/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.wjziv.com/now/</guid><description>What is a Now Page?
Updated: 2021-02-16
Personal Introspective I&amp;rsquo;ve become much more comfortable with the WFH groove I&amp;rsquo;ve found for myself. I&amp;rsquo;ve proposed to my beautifully capable girlfriend (now fiance). And I&amp;rsquo;ve re-watched nearly the entirety of Chuck.
Things are looking up, and I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to focusing this energy in all the right areas.
Activity Once again, I feel comfortable with how things are going! My self-organization is pointed at a small group of applications I&amp;rsquo;ve used previoously, along with a new one (Shout out to Fullscreen For Google Tasks!</description></item><item><title>Resources</title><link>https://www.wjziv.com/resources/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.wjziv.com/resources/</guid><description>Here are some interesting datasets, websites, and educational spots which I don&amp;rsquo;t have enough to comment on, but I think they still deserve a shout-out.
Product Description Google-Colab Code in an online Python IDE and execute blocks by segment. ObservableHQ Code in an online JS IDE and execute blocks by segment; geared towards interactive visualization. Kaggle Crowd-sourced datasets, a data-scienced focused community, paid competitions, and great technical tutorials.</description></item><item><title>Resume</title><link>https://www.wjziv.com/resume/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.wjziv.com/resume/</guid><description>Experience Alchemy Worx Cloud Engineer, January 2019 - Present
Lead the construction of the company&amp;rsquo;s backend from scratch, primarily using Python on GCP. Scheduled ETL process through Flask, and enabled internal team to interact with data through Slackbot API Integration. Design CI/CD pipelines to improve building processes. Internal and client-facing report generation on the fly. Web-based, interactive dashboards on the way! Constant communication with the strategy team to find out how they use their tools and what they need to do their job better.</description></item></channel></rss>