<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>recipe on Walter Zielenski</title><link>https://www.wjziv.com/tags/recipe/</link><description>Recent content in recipe on Walter Zielenski</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.wjziv.com/tags/recipe/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Josh's* Challa Bread</title><link>https://www.wjziv.com/20210705-joshs-challah/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.wjziv.com/20210705-joshs-challah/</guid><description>My sister&amp;rsquo;s husband Josh didn&amp;rsquo;t actually create this recipe for bread. It was only with him that I ever made challah for the first time. Proper credit goes to Beth Ricanati.
When we first made this recipe, it had the dense, squishy texture one might expect of an open-oven baked bread with little rise-time. I fully intend to return to this recipe with improvements with regard to rise time, baking in a dutch-oven, and weaving to fit inside a small pan.</description></item><item><title>Serious Eats' Workhorse Loaf</title><link>https://www.wjziv.com/20200108-serious-eats-workhorse-loaf/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.wjziv.com/20200108-serious-eats-workhorse-loaf/</guid><description>Serious Eats has a spectacular recipe for a hand-made loaf of whitebread. The only problem is that there are two versions. The short version skips a few steps which improve the rising process. The 5-part long version includes everything for a delicious loaf, but it takes 37 years to read through it all for the action steps.
The first time you make a bread loaf, I recommend you follow along the long-form recipe on the Serious Eats website to find out the &amp;lsquo;right way&amp;rsquo; to execute things like a &amp;lsquo;fold&amp;rsquo; or read up on tips for transferring dough from one bowl to another.</description></item><item><title>Aunt Jo's Christmas Ricotta Cookies</title><link>https://www.wjziv.com/20200107-aunt-jos-cookies/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.wjziv.com/20200107-aunt-jos-cookies/</guid><description>Everybody has an aunt with their own way of making those Italian Christmas cookies.
And I&amp;rsquo;ve discovered that my Aunt Jo has at some point shifted to a second recipe. The time of transition is unknown, and which is the old/new version is a mystery; I simply refuse to ask, because I haven&amp;rsquo;t noticed the difference over time, and I can only dream that I grew on on a &amp;ldquo;better cookie&amp;rdquo;, whicher it may be.</description></item></channel></rss>