<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>how-to on Walter Zielenski</title><link>https://www.wjziv.com/tags/how-to/</link><description>Recent content in how-to on Walter Zielenski</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.wjziv.com/tags/how-to/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About This Site</title><link>https://www.wjziv.com/20201126-this-website/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.wjziv.com/20201126-this-website/</guid><description>Summary Host a personal website on Github using the Hugo site generator. Updates to content will be incorporated into the site via triggered Github Actions.
My Choices Originally, I was using Frozen-Flask and FlatPages to build my static site. Flask, as backend tool I was familiar with, was something I was interested in leveraging for this website. Ultimately, it felt like a hodge-podge project, loosely slapped together which could have been executed in a better way.</description></item><item><title>VSCode on the Cloud</title><link>https://www.wjziv.com/20200426-vscode-server/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.wjziv.com/20200426-vscode-server/</guid><description>Goal Using Google Cloud Platform, host an instance of VSCode to access via the browser for ~$25-$50/month. More specifically, we&amp;rsquo;ll be hosting an instance of Code-Server on GCP in a constantly-running VM.
This works as an alternative to the cloud-development environments which may limit the developer in some way:
Number of private repositories Working Hours in a given period Number of projects Repository integration. Requirements This tutorial assumes you have already set up a GCP account and enabled billing.</description></item><item><title>Installing Python on ChromeOS</title><link>https://www.wjziv.com/20200105-python-on-chromeos/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.wjziv.com/20200105-python-on-chromeos/</guid><description>Have a Chromebook? Don&amp;rsquo;t have Python installed? Or worse, have Python2 and you&amp;rsquo;d rather have Python3? Let&amp;rsquo;s fix that!
To start out, I want to share a picture from XKCD:
Python is notorious for its ability to lull the developer into a false sense of security before they absentmindedly mis-manage their coding environment. It&amp;rsquo;s unfortunate, and not exactly necessary for a language to require this. Go ahead and search for the golang python enviroment equivalent.</description></item><item><title>SFTP Server Setup</title><link>https://www.wjziv.com/20200104-sftp-server/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.wjziv.com/20200104-sftp-server/</guid><description>Assuming the user has already created a VM with a static IP address open to HTTP/S traffic&amp;hellip;
Creating An SFTP Account SSH into the VM which you&amp;rsquo;d like to turn into a SFTP server.
Create a new account which you&amp;rsquo;d like to provide to users to deposit files:
sudo adduser username sudo passwd username Create the sftp directory and limit the user&amp;rsquo;s access and permissions. Change the username appropriately:</description></item><item><title>GCP VM Setup for Squid Proxy and SFTP</title><link>https://www.wjziv.com/20200103-gcp-vm-setup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.wjziv.com/20200103-gcp-vm-setup/</guid><description>Assuming the user has already opened a GCP Account and enabled billing&amp;hellip;
The goal of this tutorial is to create a server which will be responsive to external HTTP requests for the purpose of serving external users a FTP server to drop files, or operate as an authenticated proxy.
VM Set Up Open Compute Engine &amp;gt; VM Instances. Createa new Instance. (NOTE. If you would like to create a template from which more instances can be made, perform the following steps from Instance Templates.</description></item><item><title>Squid Proxy Server Setup</title><link>https://www.wjziv.com/20200103-squid-proxy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.wjziv.com/20200103-squid-proxy/</guid><description>These instructions assume you have successfully completed the following:
Opened a GCP account. Set up a VM with a static IP address and open HTTP/HTTPS ports. The goal of these instrctions is to create a functional proxy VM on GCP.
Port Rules With your VM already created and tagged correctly, navigate to VPC Network &amp;gt; Firewall Rules. Here, a number of networking rules have been created. We will be editing the HTTP/S port rules.</description></item></channel></rss>